Guide to the Donald Clifford Gallup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- April 2001 Acquisition, 1866-2000; 14; 78.5; (87 boxes) + 4 record album storage, 4 art, 1 object storage
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Pound, Ezra
      - Transcripts, photostats, photocopies, and publications of Ezra Pound correspondence
        - Oppenheim, James, undated
        - Paquette, Donald J., undated
        - Parks, H. B., undated
        - Pinker, J. B., undated
        - Pound, Homer L. & I., undated
        - Santini, undated
        - Schilling, Felix, undated
        - Schwartz, Mr., undated
        - Seymour, R. F., undated
        - Sharpe, Mr., undated
        - Simpson, Cynthia, undated
        - Swabey, Henry, undated
        - Taylor, Rachel Annand, undated
        - Theobald, John, undated
        - Verschoyle, Derek, undated
        - Woodward, William, undated
        - Wykes, Joyce, undated
        - Yale Literature, undated
      - Portraits, undated
      - The Pound Newsletter, #1, 3, 1954
    - Pound, Omar S., 1961-1996
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1937-1996
    - Princeton University Press, undated
    - Pringle, Aileen, circa 1957-1962
    - Prokosch, Frederic, 1951-1991
    - Purdy, James, 1958-1968; 5
    - Purdy, James, circa 1957-1996; 11 (Box 56)
    - Quinby, Jane, 1948-1972
    - Quinn, Mary Bernetta, 1967-1989; 6; (includes 3 audiocassettes)
      Includes recordings entitled: "Robert Penn Warren - Birthday Salute!, 1987"; "Robert Penn Warren, 1989"; "Listen, and Play It For Whom"
    - Quinn, Mary Bernetta, 1969, undated; 2 (Box 57)
    - "R" General, circa 1950-1990
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, circa 1957-1996; 6
    - Rachewiltz, Patricia de, 1974-2000
    - Rachewiltz, Walter de, 1968, undated
    - Radwany, Emery, 1950, undated
    - Rainey, Lawrence S., 1983-1992, undated
    - Randall, Dave, undated
    - Random House, 1940-1973, undated
    - Rannit, Aleksis, circa 1967-1985
    - Ray, Gordon N., 1965-1974; 2
    - Read, Forrest, 1972-1978
    - Reed, Joe & Kit, circa 1980-1993
    - Reese, William, 1984-1987, undated
    - Regnery, Henry, 1969-1970
    - Review, 1986
    - Richards, David A., 1998
    - Riding, Laura, circa 1952-1991
    - Riely, John & Beth, 1980-1987 (Box 58)
    - Robinson, James, 1998
    - Robinson, Pamela, 1987-2000
    - Rochester, 1985-1992, undated; 3
    - Roemer, Michael, 1997
    - Rogers, Bill & Mildred, 1947-1973, undated
    - Rogers, Rutherford, 1969-1989
    - Rollins, Carl P., 1936-1996
    - Rose, Francis, 1947-1986
    - Rose, W. K., 1964-1968, undated
    - The Rosenbach Museum & Library, 1993, undated
    - The Rosenbach Newsletter, 1993 November 5
    - Ross, David S., undated
    - Rota, Bertram, 1935-1982; 16
    - Rota, Bertram, 1983-1999, undated (Box 59)
    - Rota, Una, 1969-1972
    - Roule, Trifin, 1999-2000
    - Rudge, Olga, 1957-1997
    - Russell, Peter, circa 1949-1977
    - Rutgers University, 1974-1976
    - Ryskamp, Charles, 1989-1997
    - "S" General, 1959-1996
    - Sachse, William L., 1938-2000
    - Sammons, Christa, 1986-2000
    - Sampter, Lawrence & Ruth, 1965-1974
    - Samsonite, undated
    - Sancetta, Joyce, 1981-1999
    - Sawyer, Julian, 1941-1982
    - Schaffner, John & Perdita, 1961-2000
    - Scheetz, Nicholas B., 1997
    - Scheiwiller, Vanni, 1957-1988, undated
    - Scheuer, E., 1951-1961, undated
    - The Scholar's Bookshelf, 1961-1992
    - Schoonover, David, 1986-1988
    - Schulte's Book Store, Inc., 1935-1940
    - Schwartz, Jacob, circa 1948-1971
    - Scott, Laurence, 1963-1986
    - The Scribner Book Store, 1949-1963
    - Seldes, Gilbert, 1969-1970
    - Seven Gables, 1938-1968
    - Shaheen, Mohammad, 1994-1995, undated
    - Shaughnessy, Edward L., 1998
    - Scheaffer, Louis, 1968-1986
    - Silver, Rollo, 1972-1988
    - Simmonds, Harvey, 1968-1976
    - Sims, G. F., circa 1954-1979
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1949, undated (Box 60)
    - Slavitt, David R., 1993-1998
    - Slocum, John J., 1957-1990
    - Smidt, Kristian, 1948-1973
    - Smith, Alan A., 1954-1956
    - Smith, Evelyn, 1970-1995
    - Smith, Grover, 1949-2000
    - Smith, Warren, 1973-1989
    - Smith, William Jay, 1966-1981, undated
    - SNET, undated
    - Soldo, John J., circa 1990-1986
    - Sotheby's, 1990
    - Southern Methodist University, 1999
    - Southern Review, 1984-1987
    - Southwest Review, 1939-1987
    - The Southworth-Anthoensen Press, 1937-1948, undated
    - Spratling, William, 1987 December 17
    - Stam, David, 1999
    - Stechert - Hafner, circa 1939-1999
    - Stein, Gertrude
      - Correspondence of Donald Gallup regarding Gertrude Stein
        - Booksellers
          - "A - Z" General, 1946-1950
          - The New Colophon, 1949-1951
        - Individuals
          - "A - Z" General, circa 1969-1998
          - Gill, John, 1980-1986
          - Huebsch, B. W., 1959, undated
          - Levin, Calman A., 1963-1997
          - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1948
          - Steward, Samuel M., 1977, undated
          - Sturm, Oliver, 1999
        - Libraries, 1941-1986, undated
        - Publishers, 1940-1992, undated
      - Photocopies and transcripts of Gertrude Stein correspondence
        - Buss, Kate, undated
        - Gallup, Donald, undated; 3
        - Graves, Robert, 1981, undated
        - Hartley, Marsden, undated
        - Lachenal, François, undated
        - McAlmon, Robert, undated
        - Maratier, Georges, undated
      - Catalogue, undated (Box 61)
      - The Flowers of Friendship, 1935-1953; 4
      - Three Lives, 1947, undated
      - Photographs and negatives, undated
    - Stephens, James, undated
    - Stevens, E. & J., 1968-1981
    - Stevens, Holly, 1964-1999
    - Stieglitz, Alfred & O'Keeffe, Georgia
      - "A - Z" General, circa 1989-1998; 5
      - Fahlman, Betsy, 1996
      - Greenough, Sarah, 1986-1992
      - Brennan, Marica, 1999 September 30
      - Hamilton, Juan, circa 1983-1988
      - Kiefer, Geraldine W., 1990
      - Mellby, Julie, 1993
      - O'Keeffe Foundation, circa 1988-1999
      - Peters, Sarah Whitaker, circa 1988-1999
      - Pollitzer, William S., 1984-1990
      - Pomegranate, 1997, undated
      - Rathbone, Belinda, 1986-1988
      - Stieglitz Archive, undated
    - Stimson, George P., circa 1949-1999
    - Stock, Noel, 1961-2000 (Box 62)
    - Stone, Bernard, 1961-1973
    - Stonehill, C. A., 1935-1946
    - Strand, Paul, 1966-1968
    - Strand, Mark, undated
    - Strand Book Store, Inc., circa 1966-1992
    - Sullivan, Edward D. S., 1964-1981
    - Sutton, John F., 1988-1999
    - Sweeney, John L., 1947-1950
    - Sze, Mai-Mai, 1956
    - Szladita, Lola, 1968-1990
    - "T" General, circa 1959-1998
    - Tanis, James & Florence, 1970-1987, undated
    - Tanselle, Tom, 1970-1994
    - Taylor, Prentiss, 1955-1986, undated
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1952-1969
    - Texas, circa 1956-1992; 4
    - Tharp, Charles, 1975 October 10
    - Thomas, Alan G., 1960-1969
    - Thomson, Virgil, circa 1951-1986
    - Ticknor & Fields, 1978-1984, undated
    - The Times Bookshop, 1961-1967, undated
    - The Times Literary Supplement, undated
    - Tinker, Chauncey B., 1935-1994
    - Tinkle, Lon, 1939-1985
    - Toklas, Alice B., 1946-1950
    - Toklas, Alice B., 1951-1973, undated; 5 (Box 63)
    - Toledo, 1971-1986, undated; 3
    - Townsend, Ben, 1955-1965, undated
    - Tunley, Roul, 1947-1993
    - "U" General, 1952-1990
    - University of Buffalo Libraries, 1937-1997, undated
    - University of Chicago Library, 1961-1995
    - University of Mississippi, 1979
    - Uphill, Arthur, 1974-1999
    - "V" General, 1969-1996
    - Van Nosdall, George A., 1961
    - Van Sinderen Prizes, 1957-1958
    - Van Vechten, Carl
      - Permissions
        - "A - Z" General, 1929-1996, undated; 3
        - Columbia Oral History, 1971-1981
        - Hallmark, 1989-1991
      - Adaptations
        - The Blind Bow Boy, 1972
        - Nigger Heaven, 1975-1985
        - Parties, undated
        - Peter Whiffle, 1979
        - Spider Boy, 1979
        - Tattooed Countess, 1985-1991
      - Biography, 1978-1982
      - Solomon, Jerry, 1996-1997
      - Photographs, 1973-1981
    - Van Vechten, Fania, 1953-1971, undated
    - Van Vechten, Solomon, 1969-1984; 2
    - Van Vechten, Solomon, 1985-1996; 3 (Box 64)
    - Virginia, 1938-1998, undated
    - Vogel, Joseph, 1970
    - Vuilleumier, Norman E., 1997-1999
    - "W" General, circa 1941-1991
    - Wagner, Martin & Linda, 1969-1995, undated
    - Waith, Eugene, 1947-1999, undated
    - Walker, Hudson D., 1975-1976
    - Walker, Margaret, 1989
    - Wallace, Emily, 1968-1993
    - Wallrich, L. A., 1962-1974
    - Walsh, John, 1981-1994
    - Warren, Robert Penn, circa 1968-1989
    - Watson, Steven, 1986-1996
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw, 1961 September 3
    - Weber, Robert L., 1967-1980
    - Weeks, Mabel Foote, 1947-1953
    - Wellek, René, 1947-1999, undated
    - Wenning, Henry W., circa 1959-1988; 2
    - Werner, Arno, 1962, undated
    - Whelpley, Anne, 1965-2000, undated
    - White, George Abbott, 1982-1989, undated
    - Who's Who, 1977-1999, undated
    - Wilder, Amos Tappan, 1977-1997, undated
    - Wilder, Amos Tappan, circa 1988-1996; 2 (Box 65)
    - Wilder, Catherine, 1975-1998
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1969 April 11
    - Wilder, Isabel, 1953-1994; 9
    - Wilder, Janet, 1983-1989
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1950-1985, undated; 4
      - Correspondence of Donald Gallup regarding Thornton Wilder
        - Unsorted correspondence, 1950-1975
        - Aikkola, Margaret Walbridge, 1986-1995
        - American Association of University Women, 1985, undated
        - Anderson, E. G., 1976
        - Brunauer, Dalma H., undated (Box 66)
        - Feshbach, Sidney, 1994, undated
        - Glowacki, Stanley, 1982-1989
        - Greene, Waldo, 1980-1988
        - Laswell, Mary, 1986-1988
        - Layton, William, 1991-1992
        - Nardi, Marcia, 1991, undated
        - The New Criterion, 1985, undated
        - "Our Town", 1993
        - Walsh, Claudette M., 1986-1997
        - Wilder Books, 1989
        - Wolter, Jürgen, 1983-1984
      - Photocopies and Booksellers' Descriptions of Thornton Wilder correspondence
        - Brieff, Frank, undated
        - Hays, Helen, undated
        - Hemingway, Ernest, undated
        - Janta, Aleksander, undated
        - Knopf, Alfred A., undated
        - Miłosz, Czesław, undated
        - Moffitt, Mr., undated
        - Saltalamacchia, Anthony, undated
        - Schaefer, Hans Joachim, undated
    - Wilentz, Theodore, 1973-1998, undated
    - Wilhelm, James J., 1985-1990
    - Williams, Herschel, 1967-1981
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1979, undated
    - Willis, Pat, 1985-1987
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1942-1990
    - Wilson, Robert, 1960-1988; 2
    - Windham, Donald & Campbell, Sandy, 1976-1995
    - Windows, 1984-1990
    - Wing, Donald Goddard, 1952-1997, undated
    - Winks, Robert, 1984-1986
    - Winship, Michael, 1997
    - Winterbotham, Joseph, 1950-1954
    - Wise, T. J., undated
    - Witemeyer, Hugh, 1966-1988
    - Witherspoon, A. M., 1934-1992, undated; 2
    - Witten, Laurence, 1970-1988
    - Wolf, Edwin, 1992 February 10
    - Wood, Roger, 1987-1988
    - Wood, Thomas M., 1987
    - Woolmer, Howard, 1966-1998
    - Worth, Irene, 1995, undated
    - Wroth, Lawrence C., 1946-1956 (Box 67)
    - Wylie, Max, undated
    - Wynne, Marjorie, 1963-1999
    - Wytfliet, Cornelius, 1946-1992, undated; 3
    - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1991-1993
    - The Yale Bibliophiles, 1972-1987
    - Yale Club of New York, 1947-1993
    - Yale Co-Op Bookstore, 1996, undated
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, 1959
    - The Yale Review, 1947-1997, undated; 2
    - Yale University
      - Unsorted correspondence, 1946-1999; 2
      - Alumni Fund, 1969-1997
      - Art Gallery, 1956-1998; 3
      - Beinecke Library, 1962-1998, undated; 2
      - British Art Center, 1990-1997, undated; 3
      - Class of 1934, 1951-1997, undated
      - Drama School, 1933-1937
      - Franklin, Ralph, 1982-2000
      - The Friends of Music at Yale, 1986-1998
      - Graduate School, 1993-1998
      - Health Services, 1972-1996
      - Honorable Company of College Printers, circa 1979-1991
      - Library Associates, 1987-1998, undated
      - Yale University Library, 1937-2000; 4
      - Yale University Press, 1947-1992; 2
      - Yale University Press, 1992-1999, undated; 3 (Box 68)
    - Yeats, W. B., undated
    - Zeid, Princess, 1949-1950
    - Zeitlin, Jake, 1986
  - Other Papers
    Arranged in no particular order as received by the library.
    - Card files, undated; 2 (Box 69)
    - Music scores with lyrics by T. S. Eliot, circa 1948-1976; 4
    - Newspaper clippings and other printed material, circa 1955-1999; 5 (Box 70)
    - Bawden, E. "Winter the Huntsman"; original sketch, 1962, undated
    - Davie, Donald. Essex Poems, 1971, undated
    - Horgan, Paul; two original drawings, undated
    - Gray, John Edward; autograph letter signed, 1866 April 18
    - Correspondence of Harold Monro, circa 1909-1929; 8
    - Unsorted notes, undated
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1997-2000; 3
    - The Flowers of Friendship, 1953, undated; 2
    - Transcripts of Gertrude Stein correspondence, undated
    - T. S. Eliot; a bibliography, 1975-1992, undated; 25 (Box 71)
      Includes early drafts, master copy of 1969, newspaper clippings, and other printed material.
    - Papers of Townsend Miller
      - Printed material and photographs, 1964-1965 (Box 72)
      - Notebooks, undated
      - Miscellanous manuscripts, undated; 4
      - "Aeneid", undated
      - "Apassionata", undated
      - "A Book of Arts", undated
      - Chaucer, 1933, undated
      - The "Pop-Up" Buck Rogers, 1934
      - Bibliographic index cards, undated
      - "Christ-Church Hymns", undated
      - "To Help My Husband," "Unfinished Symphony," "Love Is For Two", 1947
      - "Desert Twilight", undated
      - Eastman, undated
      - "Elegia Quinta: the Great Western", 1941-1997
      - "The Gothic Cathedral as an Exemplification of Form", undated
      - "I am Sorry But I Cannot Love You", undated
      - "Julian", 1931
      - Keats, undated
      - "A Letter from Texas", 1939-1944; 2
      - "Little Boy Lost", undated
      - Furioso, Vol. I, No. 4, 1941
        Includes "Six Lyrics" by T. Miller.
      - "Marathon", undated
      - "Masefield Purge Poem", undated
      - Meredith, undated
      - "A Modern Litany", 1939
      - "Myth", 1934; 2
      - Notebook [Poems], 1935, undated; 2
      - Phi Beta Kappa poem, undated (Box 73)
      - "The Pipes of Pan", undated
      - "Prologue to a Projected Poem of Joan of Arc", undated
      - "The Runes", undated
      - "San Antonio: 1938", undated
      - "Sedia Gestatoria", undated
      - "Songs for the Season", undated
      - Sonnets, undated
      - "Sung at Dawning", 1928, undated
      - "This Is What I Saw", undated
      - "Three Songs For Singers", undtaed
      - "Translations from the OE", undated
      - Tristia, undated
      - "No Heartbreak in the Night" And Other Poems, 1932
      - Trojan War, undated
      - "Troy", undated
      - "Valediction", undated
      - Vernon poems, undated
      - "Winter Sonnet", 1929?
      - "You Are Dying", undated
      - Letters from Townsend Miller to Donald Gallup, 1936-1975; 9
      - American Mercury, 1936 March (Box 74)
      - Books New York Herald Tribune, 1963 September 1
      - Experiment, 1945 Summer
      - Furioso, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1939 Summer
      - The Harkness Hoot, 1932-1933
      - Personal Romances, 1946-1949; 5
      - Poetry World, 1934 July
      - Romantic Story, 1942 January
      - Southwest Review, 1937 October
      - Today's Woman, 1949 January
      - True Confessions, 1949 November
      - True Story, 1949 April
      - Voices, 1935 Autumn
      - The Yale Literary Magazine, 1933 February
      - Yale Review, 1936 Winter
    - What Mad Pursuits, 1998, undated; 9
      Includes early drafts and final version.
    - What Mad Pursuits, undated; 9 (Box 75)
    - Bibliography of American Literature, 1961-1991, undated; 2
    - Newspaper clippings and other printed ephemera
      - To Be Filed, 1969-1993, undated
      - The Dial, 1965-1987
      - Eliot, T. S., 1994-1998, undated; 2
      - Epstein, Jacob, 1958-1961
      - Gallup, Donald, 1939-1995, undated; 9
      - Garbo, Greta, 1926
      - Greene, Graham, 1992-1994
      - Hartley, Marsden, 1954-1993; 2
      - John, Augustus, 1941-1961, undated
      - Bates, J. E., 1961-1991
      - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry, 1949-1971, undated
      - Lascaux, Elie, 1958, undated
      - Laughlin, James, 1986, undated
      - Lear, Edward, undated
      - Leiris, Michel, 1978-1993
      - Monro, Harold, 1967-1983
      - Murdock, Jan, 1995, undated
      - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1971-1995, undated; 4
      - O'Neill, Eugene, 1967-1994, undated; 2
      - O'Neill, Eugene, 1988-1998, undated; 2 (Box 76)
      - Piaf, Edith, 1947
      - Pound, Ezra, 1997, undated
      - Quedlinburg, 1990-1992, undated
      - Quinn, John, 1968-1989
      - Stein, Gertrude, 1946-1993, undated; 11
      - Steloff, Frances, 1965-1991
      - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1982-1983; 2
      - Van Vechten, Carl, circa 1971-1993
      - Vaughan, Keith, 1952
      - Wilder, Thornton, 1969-1997; 9
    - Material about or relating to T. S. Eliot
      - General, 1949-1970, undated (Box 77)
      - Biographical, 1948-1986
      - Miscellaneous, 1965, undated
      - Nobel Prize, 1948-1949
      - Portraits, 1949-1958, undated
      - Bel Esprit, 1922 July 8
      - "The Cocktail Party", circa 1949-1951; 2
      - Rooming - Applications, circa 1955-1988
      - Collected poems, 1954-1969
      - "The Confidential Clerk", 1952-1954, undated; 2
      - The Criterion, 1968-1981
      - "The Cultivation of Christmas Trees", 1954-1956
      - Cimarron Review, 1975 January
      - Du Bos, Charles, 1959
      - "East Coker", 1940
      - "The Elder Statesman", 1958-1962; 2
      - Essays, 1936-1956
      - "The Family Reunion", 1956-1962, undated; 2
      - For Lancelot Andrews, 1928-1970 (Box 78)
      - "Four Quartets", 1943-1986
      - "The Frontiers of Criticism", undated
      - Harvard reading, 1955 May 29
      - Huxley, Aldous, 1965-1966
      - The Idea of a Christian Society, 1939, undated
      - Illustrations, 1950-1974, undated
      - Interviews, 1955-1965
      - Introductions, 1946-1971, undated
      - Juvenilia, 1956 November 26
      - Kipling, Rudyard, undated
      - Knowledge and Experience in the Philosophy of F. H. Bradley, 1964, undated
      - The Letters of T. S. Eliot, 1988
      - "The Literature of Politics", 1955 September 30
      - "Little Gidding", 1943-1966
      - Milton, 1947
      - "Murder in the Cathedral", 1937-1958, undated; 3
      - "The Music of Poetry", 1959 November 8
      - New English Bible, 1961-1962
      - Notes, 1948-1949
      - Clippings about catalogs, 1981-1987, undated; 2
      - Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats, 1952, undated
      - On Poetry and Poets, 1957, undated
      - "On Teaching the Appreciation of Poetry", 1960-1961
      - Poems, 1920-1977
      - "Poetry and Drama", 1951, undated
      - Points of View, 1941 November 8
      - Prufrock and Other Observations, 1967, undated
      - Recordings, 1930-1959
      - "The Rock", undated
      - The Sacred Wood, 1921-1951
      - "The Social Function of Poetry", 1953-1961, undated
      - "Sweeney Agonistes", 1968-1972
      - The Three Voices of Poetry, 1953-1954
      - "To Criticize the Critic", 1961-1966
      - Waste Land, 1923-1973, undated; 2
      - The "lost" manuscripts of T. S. Eliot, 1968-1969
      - Titles, 1961-1987, undated
      - Books about, A - Z, circa 1948-1984; 3
      - Announcements, etc., 1988, undated
      - Miscellaneous catalogs and announcements, 1981, undated
      - Celebrations, 1988, undated (Box 79)
      - Exhibitions, 1988
      - Portraits, undated
      - Quotes, blurbs, etc., 1952-1963, undated
      - T. S. Eliot Society, 1992-1993
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1945-1990; 3
      - Arizona Quarterly, 1974 Spring
      - Banerjee, Ron D. K. "Dante Through the Looking Glass: Rossetti, Pound, and Eliot", undated
      - Bollier, E. P. "A Broken Coriolanus", 1967-1978, undated
      - Brooker, Jewel Spears. "The Structure of Eliot's Gerontion", undated
      - Bunting, Basil. "Mr. T. S. Eliot", 1932 September 8
      - Catlin, George. "T. S. Eliot and the Moral Issue", 1949 July 2
      - Christian, Henry. "Thematic Development in T. S. Eliot's Hysteria", undated
      - Davie, Donald, 1984, undated
      - Day, Robert Adams. Joyce's Waste Land and Eliot's Unknown God, undated
      - Ellmann, Richard, 1965
      - English, 1966 Autumn
      - Frank, Armin Paul, 1971, undated
      - Giroux, Robert, 1988, undated
      - Hayward, John, 1966, undated
      - Englische Studien, 1935
      - Hirsch, David H. "T. S. Eliot and the Vexation of Time", undated
      - Imagi, 1949 Winter
      - Leitch, Vincent B. "Religious Vision in Modern Poetry", 1974
      - MacKenzie, Phyllis. "Milton's Visual Imagination", 1946 October
      - Matthews, T. S. "En Route to Waste Land", 1974 January
      - Oxford, undated
      - Ozick, Cynthia, 1989, undated
      - Panichas, George A. "T. S. Eliot and the Critique of Liberalism", 1974 Spring
      - Powel, Harford. "T. S. Eliot: A Schoolboy Poet", 1957 January
      - Princeton University. Concluding Bicentennial Convocation, undated
      - Raine, Craig, 1973
      - Redman, Ben Ray. "T. S. Eliot: In Sight of Posterity", 1949 March 12
      - Robbins, Rossell H. "A Possible Analogue for The Cocktail Party", undated
      - Schuchard, Ronald, 1973-1981
      - Schmidt, Benno, undated
      - Schmidt, Gerd, undated
      - Shapiro, Karl. "T. S. Eliot: The Death of Literary Judgement", 1959-1960
      - Spender, Stephen, 1948
      - Steinberg, Erwin R. "Mrs. Dalloway and T. S. Eliot's Personal Waste Land", undated
      - Stock, Noel, undated
      - Time, 1950
      - The American Scholar, 1947 Autumn
      - Whiteside, 1973 February
      - Wilson, Edmund, 1958 May 24
      - Yale, 1947
      - Clippings about, circa 1958-1981
      - Books in catalogs, 1970-1986
      - Books in catalogs, 1963-1990, undated; 3 (Box 80)
      - A - Z, undated
      - Letters in catalogs, A - Z, circa 1954-1986; 2
      - Eliot, Valerie, 1980-1984
      - The Notebook, notes, etc., undated
      - The Waste Land, notes, etc., undated
      - "Lost" manuscript, undated; 2
      - "A Note on the Exhibition", 1976 January 26
    - Walk Diary, 1974-1994; 18
    - Calendar, notes, 1980
    - War Diary, undated
    - Picasso - Gris, 1948, undated; 2
      Includes notes, drafts, and printed material.
    - Marsden Hartley paper & talk, undated
    - Gibson, R. W. "Thomas More: A Bibliography", 1959, undated
    - "Baretti's Reputation in England", undated
    - "Some Notes on Ezra Pound and Censorship", undated
    - "Introducing Gertrude Stein", undated
    - Appendix B, undated
    - A book is a book (empty folder), undated
    - Printed material, 1946-1980; 2
    - Aeneid, Books 1-3, undated
    - Gallup, 1973-1982, undated; 2
    - Pigeons on the Granite, 1945-1974, undated; 4 (Box 81)
      Includes photographs and drafts.
    - Original drawing by Walter Roveroni, 1941 June 28
    - Translations into German, undated
    - Yale Collection of American Literature, undated
    - Appendix A, 1933-1935, undated
    - Fanshawe, undated
    - Notes, undated
    - Little Review, undated
    - The Flowers of Friendship, undated
    - "Pigeons Is People", undated
    - "Collecting Lawrence Durrell", undated
    - "Elie Lascaux", undated
    - "Collecting Edward Lear", 1987, undated
    - "The Lost Eliot Manuscript", 1968
    - "The Calms of Capricorn", 1968-1981
    - "At Renishaw Hall With the Sitwells", 1949
    - Notebook, undated